Finding aid for the L.A. Watts Times newspapers and ephemera collection LSC.2122
UCLA Library Special Collections
L.A. Watts Times newspapers and ephemera
1987-2010
UCLA Library Special Collections
L.A.Watts Times
LSC.2122
13.8 Linear Feet (33 flat boxes)
The Watts Times was founded in 1965 following the Watts Riots. In 1976, Charles Cook purchased the publication and changed the name to L.A. Watts Times. The collection consists of original L.A. Watts Times newspapers, a small amount of awards, and a very small amount of ephemera.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Danny Bakewell, Chairman of Bakewell Media, 2012.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9973975893606533
Biography/History
The Watts Times was founded in 1965 following the Watts Riots and eventually became the premiere African American publication in Los Angeles. In 1976, the newspaper was purchased by Charles Cook, an African American activist and former leader of the Congress of Racial Equality. As an effort to include news about Los Angeles' entire African American community, Cook changed the publication's name to L.A. Watts Times. Cook was credited for transforming the L.A. Watts Times from being a tabloid circulated in Watts to becoming a financially stable weekly publication distributed in Los Angeles, Long Beach, Carson, Compton, Inglewood, Gardena, Santa Monica and West Hollywood.
After Charles Cook's death in 1998, his daughter Melanie Polk became publisher of L.A. Watts Times. In June 2010, Polk sold the publication to Danny Bakewell, publisher of Los Angeles Sentinel and owner of Bakewell Media
Scope and Content
The collection consists of issues of original L.A. Watts Times newspapers along with a small amount of awards and ephemera. The bulk of the newspapers are loose publications; a small portion are hard bound together by year. Many of the awards, honors, and commendations are from the California State Government and City of Los Angeles and they acknowledge the L.A. Watts Times as well as publishers Charles and Beverly Cook and Melanie Polk.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is not arranged.
Watts (Los Angeles, Calif.) -- Newspapers.; African Americans -- California -- Los Angeles -- Newspapers
- L.A. Watts Times, 1987 Mar-May, July-Dec; 1988 Jan-July, Sept-Oct (Box 1)
- L.A. Watts Times, 1988 Nov-1989 Sept (Box 2)
- L.A. Watts Times, 1990 Jan-1991 Dec (Box 3)
- L.A. Watts Times, 1992 Jan-1993 Mar (Box 4)
- L.A. Watts Times, 1993 Apr-Dec (Box 5)
- L.A. Watts Times, 1994 Jan-1994 Sept (Box 6)
- L.A. Watts Times, 1994 Oct-1995 July (Box 7)
- L.A. Watts Times, 1995 Aug-1996 Apr (Box 8)
- L.A. Watts Times, 1996 May, June, Aug-Dec; 1997 Jan-May (Box 9)
  Scope and Content
  All of July 1996, November 14 of 1996, January 30 of 1997, February 6 and 13 of 1997, and March 6 and 13 of 1997 are not included.
- L.A. Watts Times, 1997 June-1998 Apr (Box 10)
  June 12 and November 6 of 1997 are not included.
- L.A. Watts Times, 1998 May-1999 Jan (Box 11)
- L.A. Watts Times, 1999 Feb-1999 Nov (Box 12)
- L.A. Watts Times, 1999 Dec-2000 Aug (Box 13)
  December 16, 1999 and August 17, 2000 not included.
- L.A. Watts Times, 2000 Sept-2001 May (Box 14)
- L.A. Watts Times, 2001 June-2002 Apr (Box 15)
  May 23, 2002 is not included.
- L.A. Watts Times, 2002 May-2003 Mar (Box 16)
  December 12, 2002 is not included.
- L.A. Watts Times, 2003 Apr-2004 Apr (Box 17)
- L.A. Watts Times, 2004 May-2005 Apr (Box 18)
- L.A. Watts Times, 2005 May-2006 Apr (Box 19)
- L.A. Watts Times, 2006 May-2007 Apr (Box 20)
- L.A. Watts Times, 2007 May-2008 May (Box 21)
- L.A. Watts Times, 2008 June-2009 Apr (Box 22)
  March 19, 2009 is not included.
- L.A. Watts Times, 2009 May-2010 Mar (Box 23)
  June 11 and 18, and October 22 of 2009 are not included.
- L.A. Watts Times, 2010 Apr-Jul (Box 24)
- L.A. Watts Times (Bound), 1996 (Box 25)
- L.A. Watts Times (Bound), 1998 (Box 26)
- L.A. Watts Times (Bound), 1999 (Box 27)
- L.A. Watts Times (Bound), 2000 (Box 28)
- L.A. Watts Times (Bound), 2001 (Box 29)
- L.A. Watts Times (Bound), 2002 (Box 30)
- Awards and Honors, 1991-1995, 2006, 2007 (Box 31, Box 32)
  General
  Hanging placks.
- Awards, Honors, Commendations, Resolutions (2 folders), 1991, 1997, 2000, 2001, 2005, 2006 (Box 33)
  Many from California State Government and City of Los Angeles. Some local awards for Beverly Cook and Melanie Polk.
- Los Angeles Watts Times 25th Anniversary - ephemera, commendations, letters of congratulations, 2001 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
- City of Los Angeles in Tribute for Charles Cook (7 copies), 1998 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
- Beverly Cook - awards, 1993 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
- Melanie Polk - awards, 2000, 2001, 2006 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
- L.A. Watts Times sign (for newspaper dispenser vending machine), Undated (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
- L.A. Watts Times Newspaper press kit, 1999 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
- Photograph of Yvonne Burke, Black History Grand Marshal accepting flowers from L.A. Watts Times' Robert Reed Burns, Undated (Box 33, Folder unknown container)